Register of the Sidney Hook papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sidney Hook papers
1902-2002
90003
Hoover Institution Archives
197 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 2 envelopes, 5 sound discs (84.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, lecture notes, printed matter, sound recordings, videotape, and photographs relating to philosophy, Marxism, communism in the United States and elsewhere, the question of communists in the educational system, campus disturbances in the 1960s, the Congress for Cultural Freedom and other anti-communist movements, the thought of John Dewey, principles of education, the nature of academic freedom, and affirmative action programs.
Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989.
Access
Box 189 and tapes 19-26 in Box 185 closed. The rest of the collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990, with increments received in later years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1902 December 20 Born, New York City
1927 Ph.D., Columbia University Author, The Metaphysics of Pragmatism
1927-1969 Professor of Philosophy, Washington Square College, New York University
1933 Author, Towards the Understanding of Karl Marx
1936 Author, From Hegel to Marx
1939 Author, John Dewey: An Intellectual Portrait
1940 Author, Reason, Social Myths and Democracy
1943 Author, The Hero in History
1946 Author, Education for Modern Man
1948-1969 Head, All-University Department of Philosophy, New York University
1953 Author, Heresy, Yes, Conspiracy, No
1955 Author, Marx and the Marxists
1957 Author, Common Sense and the Fifth Amendment
1959 Author, Political Power and Personal Freedom
1961 Author, The Quest for Being
1962 Author, The Paradoxes of Freedom
1967 Author, Religion in a Free Society
1970 Author, Academic Freedom and Academic Anarchy
1973 Author, Education and the Taming of Power
1973-1989 Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
1974 Author, Pragmatism and the Tragic Sense of Life
1975 Author, Revolution, Reform and Social Justice
1980 Author, Philosophy and Public Policy
1983 Author, Marxism and Beyond
1987 Author, Out of Step: An Unquiet Life in the Twentieth Century
1989 July 12 Died, Stanford, California
1990 Author, Convictions (published posthumously)
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Sidney Hook consist of correspondence, speeches and writings, lecture notes, printed matter, sound recordings, videotape, and photographs relating to philosophy, Marxism, communism in the United States and elsewhere, the question of communists in the educational system, campus disturbances in the 1960s, the Congress for Cultural Freedom and other anti-communist movements, the thought of John Dewey, principles of education, the nature of academic freedom, and affirmative action programs.
Philosophy.; Marx, Karl, 1818-1883.; Socialism.; Communism.; Communism--United States.; Communism in education.; Student movements--United States.; Anti-communist movements.; Congress for Cultural Freedom.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Education.; Academic freedom--United States.; Liberty.; Affirmative action programs.; Philosophers.; Sound recordings.
- Biographical File, 1902-1989 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical sketches, bibliographies, correspondence, clippings, lecture notices, and other material relating to the career of Sidney Hook, arranged alphabetically by topic or physical form. See also: Addendum File.
  - Awards. Certificates, clippings, miscellany, and congratulatory letters from Michael Deaver and others, 1927-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, 1942-1977 (Folder 2-3)
  - Biographical sketches, 1950-1988 (Folder 4)
  - Biographical studies by others. Correspondence, 1958-1988. (Folder 5)
    Note: Studies relating to specific aspects of Hook's thought are filed in the Subject File
  - Birthday celebration, Program and clippings, 1982., 80th, 1982. (Folder 6)
    See also Audiovisual File
  - Clippings and printed articles
    - 1919-1955 (Folder 7)
    - 1956-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings, Pictorial, 1938-1974 (Folder 3)
  - Communist opinion. Letters, clippings, articles and translations, relating to Soviet and American communist opinion of Sidney Hook. Includes letters by J. B. S. Hardman, Granville Hicks, Wolfgang Krah and Morris U. Schappes, and an article by V. J. Jerome, 1933-1979 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1989 (Folder 5)
  - Miscellany, 1902-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Obituaries. Clippings, program, press releases, and condolence letter from George Bush, 1989. (Folder 2)
  - Quotations. Letters, typescript by James Stockdale, and printed matter, 1943-1987 (Folder 3)
  - Retirement, 1968. Clippings and congratulatory letters, 1968-1969 (Folder 4)
  - Retirement, 1973
    - Clippings, 1972-1973 (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Folder 6)
  - Trips
    - General. Identification card, memorandum, and correspondence, 1927-1966 (Folder 7)
    - Asia, 1971
      - Clippings, 1971 (Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Folder 9)
      - Miscellany, 1971 (Folder 10)
      - Schedules, 1971 (Folder 11)
    - Germany and Russia, Program and post cards, 1928-1929 (Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1921-1989 (Boxes 4-30)
  Correspondence of Sidney Hook, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. See also: Addendum File.
  - General
    - General
      - Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Unidentified (Folder 2)
      - 1923-1989 (Folder 3-5)
    - Recommendations, 1937-1989 (Folder 6)
    - Students and teaching, 1927-1988 (Folder 7)
  - Abbagnano, Nicola, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Abramovitz, Moses, 1985 (Folder 2)
  - Abrams, Elliott, 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Abt, Lawrence Edwin, 1969-1985 (Folder 4)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1938 (Folder 5)
  - Adams, Marion G., 1973-1975 (Folder 6)
  - Adelson, Joe, 1989 (Folder 7)
  - Adler, Max, 1936-1937 (Folder 8)
  - Adler, Mortimer, 1984 (Folder 9)
  - Adult Education Association of the U.S.A., 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Agassi, J., 1958 (Folder 11)
  - Albert, Ethel M., 1958 (Folder 12)
  - Alchon, Guy, 1989 (Folder 13)
  - Aldrich, Virgil, 1961 (Folder 14)
  - Alfred A. Knopf Company, 1963 (Folder 15)
  - Allard, Gerry, 1954 (Folder 16)
  - Alldredge, Charles, 1947 (Folder 17)
  - Allen, Richard V., 1981 (Folder 18)
  - Allen, Will, 1949 (Folder 19)
  - Alpern, Sara, 1983-1985 (Folder 20)
  - Alston, William P., 1956 (Folder 21)
  - Amalgamated Housing Corporation, 1964 (Folder 22)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1950-1960 (Folder 23)
  - American Affairs, 1948 (Folder 24)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1936-1987 (Folder 25)
  - American Association of University Women, 1948-1966 (Folder 26)
  - American Bar Association. Standing Committee on Education about Communism and Its Contrast with Liberty under Law, 1963-1969 (Folder 27)
  - American Broadcasting Company, 1982 (Folder 28)
  - American Catholic Philosophical Association, 1965 (Folder 29)
  - American China Policy Association (Alfred Kohlberg), 1950 (Folder 30)
  - American Committee for Emigre Scholars, Writers and Artists, 1947-1950 (Folder 31)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1946-1964 (Folder 32)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1947-1961 (Folder 33)
  - American Council on NATO, 1953 (Folder 34)
  - American Design Awards, 1950-1951 (Folder 35)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1975-1984 (Folder 36)
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1951-1954 (Folder 37)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1946-1957 (Folder 38)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1947-1974 (Folder 39)
  - American Jewish Literary Foundation, 1960 (Folder 40)
  - American Journal of Sociology, 1929 (Folder 41)
  - American League Against War and Fascism (Harry F. Ward), 1935-1948 (Folder 42)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1954 (Folder 43)
  - American Political Science Association, 1948-1978 (Folder 44)
  - American Political Science Review, 1957-1973 (Folder 45)
  - American Psychological Association, 1958 (Folder 46)
  - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, 1970 (Folder 47)
  - American Scholar, 1948-1989 (Folder 48)
  - American Schools of Oriental Research, 1948-1949 (Folder 49)
  - American Spectator (R. Emmett Tyrrell, Jr.), 1982-1988 (Folder 50)
  - American Unitarian Association, 1953 (Folder 51)
  - American Whig-Cliosophic Society, 1950 (Folder 52)
  - Amnesty International, 1983 (Folder 53)
  - Amos, Wayne, 1949 (Folder 54)
  - Anderson, John, 1938, 1987 (Folder 55)
  - Anderson, Martin, 1981-1987 (Folder 56)
  - Andrews, John K., Jr., 1985-1987 (Folder 57)
  - Andron, Mort, 1950 (Folder 58)
  - Angoff, Allan, 1957 (Folder 59)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1956-1985 (Folder 60)
  - Antioch College, 1949-1969 (Folder 61)
  - Antonovich, Michael D., 1984 (Folder 62)
  - Aristotelian Society, 1949-1951 (Folder 63)
  - Arizona. University, 1946-1959 (Folder 64)
  - Armour, Richard, 1974 (Folder 65)
  - Armstrong, David, 1972 (Folder 66)
  - Arnheim, Rudolf, 1955 (Folder 67)
  - Arnold, Thurman, 1936 (Folder 68)
  - Aronsohn, Lillian Segal, 1977-1988 (Folder 69)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1932-1943 (Folder 70)
  - Asahina, Robert, 1984-1988 (Folder 71)
  - Ascoli, Max, 1954-1969 (Folder 72)
  - Ash, Kathleen M., 1941-1974 (Folder 73)
  - Asia and World Institute, 1983 (Folder 74)
  - Asia Foundation, 1955-1960 (Folder 75)
  - Asia Society, 1959-1960 (Folder 76)
  - Atkins, Dale M., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Atkins, Elisha, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Atlas, James, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Auden, W. H., 1968-1969 (Folder 4)
  - Auerbach, Carl, 1980-1988 (Folder 5)
  - Axtelle, George E., 1952 (Folder 6)
  - Ayer, A. J., 1942-1948 (Folder 7)
  - Bacciocco, Edward J., Jr., 1982-1984 (Folder 8)
  - Bachman, Joseph P., 1987-1988 (Folder 9)
  - Bailey, Forrest, 1931 (Folder 10)
  - Bailey, J. Michael, 1988 (Folder 11)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica, 1939 (Folder 12)
  - Balch, Emily G., 1950 (Folder 13)
  - Ballantine, H. Thomas, Jr., 1949 (Folder 14)
  - Baltzly, Alexander, 1981 (Folder 15)
  - Balz, Albert G. A., 1941-1948 (Folder 16)
  - Bar-Hillel, Y., 1955 (Folder 17)
  - Bar-Levav, Reuven, 1988 (Folder 18)
  - Barcan, Rose, 1942 (Folder 19)
  - Barchas, Isaac D., 1989 (Folder 20)
  - Bard College, 1946-1949 (Folder 21)
  - Bark, Dennis, 1984-1987 (Folder 22)
  - Barnes, Albert C., 1942-1943. (Folder 23)
    See also Subject File/Russell, Bertrand
  - Baron, Joseph L., 1942 (Folder 24)
  - Barrett, William, 1946-1958 (Folder 25)
  - Bartley, William, 1985-1988 (Folder 26)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1969-1972 (Folder 27)
  - Bates, Ernest, 1939 (Folder 28)
  - Bauer-Mengelberg, Stefan, 1984-1989 (Folder 29)
  - Baumann, Fred, 1980-1989 (Folder 30)
  - Bawer, Bruce, 1985 (Folder 31)
  - Beacon Press, 1948-1952 (Folder 32)
  - Beale, Will, 1948 (Folder 33)
  - Beard, Charles A., 1930-1944 (Folder 34)
  - Beattie, Paul H., 1972-1987 (Folder 35)
  - Beatty, Jack, 1985-1988 (Folder 36)
  - Becker, Carl, 1940 (Folder 37)
  - Beichman, Arnold, 1974-1988 (Folder 38)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1942-1988 (Folder 39)
  - Bellamy, Mary, 1983-1989 (Folder 40)
  - Bellefroid, E., 1985 (Folder 41)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1988 (Folder 42)
  - Benjamin, Jack, 1961 (Folder 43)
  - Bennett, John C., 1936 (Folder 44)
  - Bennett, William J., 1982 (Folder 45)
  - Bennington College, 1936-1960 (Folder 46)
  - Bentley, Arthur F., 1957 (Folder 47)
  - Bentley, Eric, 1956 (Folder 48)
  - Berger, Samuel D., 1972 (Folder 49)
  - Bergmann, Gustav, 1970-1971 (Folder 50)
  - Berke, Jacqueline, 1970-1972 (Folder 51)
  - Berkson, I. B., 1952 (Folder 52)
  - Bernstam, Mikhail, 1983-1985 (Folder 53)
  - Bernstein, Richard, 1985-1988 (Folder 54)
  - Besangon, Alain, 1983 (Folder 55)
  - Bethell, Tom, 1987 (Folder 56)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1969 (Folder 57)
  - Bevan, Ruth A., 1968-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Billikopf, Jacob, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Billington, James H., 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Bingham, Alfred M., 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Bingham, Colin, 1967? (Folder 5)
  - Biser, Erwin, 1946 (Folder 6)
  - Black, Virginia, 1972-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Black Mountain College, 1944-1945 (Folder 8)
  - Blanshard, Brand, 1944-1985 (Folder 9)
  - Blinken, Donald M., 1985-1989 (Folder 10)
  - Bloom, Sol, 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Bluefarb, Sam, 1967-1976 (Folder 12)
  - Blum, Alex, 1962-1989 (Folder 13)
  - Blum, Edith H., 1980 (Folder 14)
  - Blumberg, Alfred, 1933 (Folder 15)
  - Boas, George, 1938-1948 (Folder 16)
  - Bochenski, I. M., 1949 (Folder 17)
  - Bodmer, Frederick, 1945 (Folder 18)
  - Boettinger, Henry M., 1969 (Folder 19)
  - Bohnert, Herbert G., 1969 (Folder 20)
  - Bondy, Francois, 1956 (Folder 21)
  - Book League of America, 1930 (Folder 22)
  - Boone, Walter S., 1989 (Folder 23)
  - Bornemann, Alfred H., 1981 (Folder 24)
  - Borovoy, A. Alan, 1980-1986 (Folder 25)
  - Boscaino, Frank, 1967 (Folder 26)
  - Boston University, 1952-1955 (Folder 27)
  - Bowers, Claude, 1942 (Folder 28)
  - Braithwaite, R. B., 1961 (Folder 29)
  - Brandeis, Louis, 1933 (Folder 30)
  - Brandeis University, 1948-1980 (Folder 31)
  - Brandt, Betty, 1967-1968 (Folder 32)
  - Brann, Henry W., 1941-1942 (Folder 33)
  - Brattleboro Reformer, 1984 (Folder 34)
  - Braude, Ben B., 1975-1982 (Folder 35)
  - Braun, Ethel, 1975-1978 (Folder 36)
  - Bremer, John, 1978 (Folder 37)
  - Bretall, Robert W., 1969 (Folder 38)
  - Bridgman, P. W., 1938 (Folder 39)
  - Brightman, Edgar S., 1936-1946 (Folder 40)
  - Brinton, Crane, 1937 (Folder 41)
  - Broad, C. D., 1922-1953 (Folder 42)
  - Brodsky, Bernard, 1985 (Folder 43)
  - Brodsky, Mrs. Ralph Howard, 1935 (Folder 44)
  - Bronstein, Daniel J., 1945-1949 (Folder 45)
  - Brookings Institution, 1958-1961 (Folder 46)
  - Brooklyn College, 1942-1968 (Folder 47)
  - Brooklyn Society for Ethical Culture, 1942-1957 (Folder 48)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1940 (Folder 49)
  - Brown, Elmer E., 1930 (Folder 50)
  - Brown, H. C., 1931 (Folder 51)
  - Brown, John M., 1958-1959 (Folder 52)
  - Brown University, 1959-1965 (Folder 53)
  - Brucker, Herbert, 1956 (Folder 54)
  - Bryan, Walter R., 1952 (Folder 55)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1948-1982 (Folder 56)
  - Brzeski, Andrzej, 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1981-1984 (Folder 58)
  - Buchanan, Patrick, 1985-1986 (Folder 59)
  - Buchanan, Scott, 1942-1943 (Folder 60)
  - Buchler, Justus, 1942 (Folder 61)
  - Buckley, Priscilla, 1984 (Folder 62)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1960-1989 (Folder 63)
  - Budenz, Mary Rodgers, 1987 (Folder 64)
  - Bullert, Gary, 1985-1986 (Folder 65)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1948-1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bunzel, John H., 1978-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Burke, Kenneth, 1933-1936 (Folder 3)
  - Burnet, John, 1923-1925 (Folder 4)
  - Burnham, James, 1938-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Burress, Richard, 1985-1988 (Folder 6)
  - Burtt, E. A., 1946-1982 (Folder 7)
  - Bush, Wendell T., 1929-1930 (Folder 8)
  - Cahn, Edmond, 1956 (Folder 9)
  - Cahn, Judah, 1968 (Folder 10)
  - Cairns, Dorion, 1938 (Folder 11)
  - Cairns, Huntington, 1941-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Caldwell, Gaylon L., 1970 (Folder 13)
  - Calhoun, Robert Lowry, 1935 (Folder 14)
  - California. University, 1948-1977 (Folder 15)
  - The Call Association, 1951 (Folder 16)
  - Calverton, V. F., 1930-1935 (Folder 17)
  - Cam, Helen, 1953 (Folder 18)
  - Cambridge University, 1962-1976 (Folder 19)
  - Campbell, Glenn, 1984-1989 (Folder 20)
  - Campbell, Norman, 1922 (Folder 21)
  - Campbell, Rita R., 1973-1975 (Folder 22)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1958-1964 (Folder 23)
  - Canadian Institute on Public Affairs, 1958 (Folder 24)
  - Cannon, Howard W., 1975 (Folder 25)
  - Capaldi, Nicholas, 1982-1987 (Folder 26)
  - Caplan, David, 1985-1989 (Folder 27)
  - Cargill, Oscar, 1952-1953 (Folder 28)
  - Carlsen, Robin Woodsworth, 1982 (Folder 29)
  - Carlson, Harry, 1969 (Folder 30)
  - Carmichael, Joel, 1984-1988 (Folder 31)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1960 (Folder 32)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1958-1959 (Folder 33)
  - Carson, Clayborne, 1985 (Folder 34)
  - Carus, M. Blouke, 1987 (Folder 35)
  - Case Western Reserve University, 1948-1967 (Folder 36)
  - Cate, Curtis, 1985-1988 (Folder 37)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1959-1977 (Folder 38)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1953-1955 (Folder 39)
  - Center for the Survival of Western Democracies, 1979 (Folder 40)
  - Chamberlain, John, 1935 (Folder 41)
  - Chamberlain, Park, 1968-1989 (Folder 42)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry, 1952 (Folder 43)
  - Chandler, Albert H., 1945 (Folder 44)
  - Chapman, John, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Chapman, S. J., 1923 (Folder 2)
  - Cheney, Lynne V., 1989 (Folder 3)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1982-1988 (Folder 4)
  - Chiaromonte, Nicola, 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Chicago. University, 1942-1968 (Folder 6)
  - Childs, John L., 1933-1968 (Folder 7)
  - Chinard, Gilbert, 1942-1943 (Folder 8)
  - Chit, Khin Myo, 1959-1960 (Folder 9)
  - Chollet, David, 1984-1987 (Folder 10)
  - Chovenson, S., 1923-1931 (Folder 11)
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, 1979 (Folder 12)
  - Christian Scholar, 1953-1958 (Folder 13)
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1989 (Folder 14)
  - Chublarian, Rouben, 1969 (Folder 15)
  - Citizens' Committee on Improvement of the Divorce Laws, 1949-1951 (Folder 16)
  - Cleve, Felix M., 1949 (Folder 17)
  - Cochran, Thomas C., 1939 (Folder 18)
  - Cogen, Charles, 1981-1989 (Folder 19)
  - Cohen, Elliot E., 1949-1952 (Folder 20)
  - Cohen, Elliott A., 1974-1979 (Folder 21)
  - Cohen, Felix, 1948 (Folder 22)
  - Cohen, Laura, 1987-1988 (Folder 23)
  - Cohen, Morris R., 1925-1943 (Folder 24)
  - Cohen, Mortimer, 1943-1947 (Folder 25)
  - Cohen, Mortimer Theodore, 1979-1981 (Folder 26)
  - Cohen, Theodore, 1983 (Folder 27)
  - Cohn, Robert G., 1974-1989 (Folder 28)
  - Coit, Stanton, 1932 (Folder 29)
  - Coker, Francis W., 1943 (Folder 30)
  - Colby, Elbridge, 1955 (Folder 31)
  - Colby, Roy, 1986 (Folder 32)
  - Coleman, Peter, 1980-1987 (Folder 33)
  - College Center of the Finger Lakes, 1966-1968 (Folder 34)
  - College of the Pacific, 1947-1956 (Folder 35)
  - College of William and Mary, 1963-1967 (Folder 36)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, 1949-1987 (Folder 37)
  - Columbia University, 1929-1982 (Folder 38)
  - Columbia University. Teachers College, 1945-1962 (Folder 39)
  - Commentary (Elliot Cohen and others), 1947-1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Commission on New Approaches to American Jewish Education, 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
  - Committee on the Present Danger, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Community Church of New York, 1948-1954 (Folder 4)
  - Compton, Arthur H., 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Conant, James B., 1949-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Condon, Edward U., 1952 (Folder 7)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1950-1960 (Folder 8)
  - Confluence (Henry Kissinger), 1953-1955 (Folder 9)
  - Conger, George P., 1949 (Folder 10)
  - Connecticut. University, 1947-1969 (Folder 11)
  - Constable, George W., 1952 (Folder 12)
  - Contemporary Jewish Record, 1945 (Folder 13)
  - Continuum (Justus George Lawler), 1963 (Folder 14)
  - The Converted Catholic, 1941-1949 (Folder 15)
  - Conze, Edward, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Coomaraswamy, Ananda K., 1945-1946 (Folder 17)
  - Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, 1939-1956 (Folder 18)
  - Copi, Irving, 1988-1989 (Folder 19)
  - Coppel, Helen, 1948 (Folder 20)
  - Corey, Lewis, 1948 (Folder 21)
  - Cornell University, 1949-1969 (Folder 22)
  - Costello, H. T., 1946 (Folder 23)
  - Costello, John E., 1984 (Folder 24)
  - Couch, William Terry, 1950-1953 (Folder 25)
  - Counts, George S., 1930-1947 (Folder 26)
  - Cowles, Gardner, 1968 (Folder 27)
  - Cox, Theodore St. John, 1947 (Folder 28)
  - Cranberg, Lawrence, 1980-1989 (Folder 29)
  - Crawshay-William, Rupert, 1947 (Folder 30)
  - Crews, Frederick, 1984-1986 (Folder 31)
  - Criterion Books, 1955-1960 (Folder 32)
  - Crocker, Lester G., 1982 (Folder 33)
  - Crossman, R. H. S., 1950-1951 (Folder 34)
  - Current Digest of the Soviet Press, 1950-1953 (Folder 35)
  - Currie, Lauchlin, 1970 (Folder 36)
  - Curti, Merle, 1932-1945 (Folder 37)
  - Czapski, Joseph, 1950 (Folder 38)
  - Daedalus, 1959-1970 (Folder 39)
  - Dallin, David J., 1948 (Folder 40)
  - Danto, Arthur, 1963 (Folder 41)
  - Darlington, C. D., 1949 (Folder 42)
  - Dartmouth College, 1947-1989 (Folder 43)
  - Das, Taraknath, 1945 (Folder 44)
  - Davenport, Russell W., 1948 (Folder 45)
  - Davis, Everly Mahin, 1948-1950 (Folder 46)
  - Davis, Harriet, 1948 (Folder 47)
  - Davis, Robert Gorham, 1953 (Folder 48)
  - Davis, Kenneth S., 1967 (Folder 49)
  - Dawidowicz, Lucy S., 1985 (Folder 50)
  - Dean, Vera Micheles, 1937 (Folder 51)
  - De Cicco, Henry, 1950-1952 (Folder 52)
  - Decter, Midge, 1975-1988 (Folder 53)
  - Decter, Moshe, 1965-1980 (Folder 54)
  - De George, Richard T., 1977 (Folder 55)
  - Degras, Jane, 1948 (Folder 56)
  - De Grazia, Alfred, 1962 (Folder 57)
  - Delattre, Edwin J., 1984-1985 (Folder 58)
  - Delaware. University, 1954-1980 (Folder 59)
  - Delta Books, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Democratic Socialist Federation of the U.S.A., 1965 (Folder 2)
  - Demos, Raphael, 1961 (Folder 3)
  - Dennen, Leon, 1948-1949 (Folder 4)
  - Dennike, George, 1948 (Folder 5)
  - De Paul University, 1965-1969 (Folder 6)
  - De Toledano, Ralph, 1948-1950 (Folder 7)
  - Devine, Philip E., 1989 (Folder 8)
  - Dial Press, 1948-1950 (Folder 9)
  - Dickey, John, 1953 (Folder 10)
  - Dickinson College, 1956-1958 (Folder 11)
  - Diggins, John P., 1971-1989 (Folder 12)
  - Dittberner, Job L., 1978 (Folder 13)
  - Dobsevage, Alvin B., 1953-1954 (Folder 14)
  - Dodd, Thomas J., 1964 (Folder 15)
  - Doino, William, Jr., 1984-1986 (Folder 16)
  - Domes, J|rgen, 1973 (Folder 17)
  - Donnelly, Ann T., 1986-1987 (Folder 18)
  - Donohue, William A., 1984-1988 (Folder 19)
  - Donovan, Hedley, 1979 (Folder 20)
  - Dorfman, Joseph, 1949 (Folder 21)
  - Dorsey, Gray L., 1977-1988 (Folder 22)
  - Dos Passos, John, 1958-1968 (Folder 23)
  - Douglas, Jack D., 1974 (Folder 24)
  - Douglas, Paul H., 1951 (Folder 25)
  - Dover Publications, 1950-1953 (Folder 26)
  - Dowling, Allan, 1973 (Folder 27)
  - Drachkovitch, Milorad M., 1972-1985 (Folder 28)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1972-1987 (Folder 29)
  - Dryden Press, 1952 (Folder 30)
  - Du Bois, W. E. B., 1945 (Folder 31)
  - Ducasse, C. J., 1940-1959 (Folder 32)
  - Duke University, 1945-1979 (Folder 33)
  - Duncan, Andrew W., 1984-1987 (Folder 34)
  - Duncan, Homer, 1984-1988 (Folder 35)
  - Dunner, Joseph, 1974-1975 (Folder 36)
  - Dupee, Frederick W., 1951 (Folder 37)
  - Dykhuizen, George, 1950 (Folder 38)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1973-1983 (Folder 39)
  - Eastman, Max, 1937-1959 (Folder 40)
  - Ebon, Martin, 1984-1987 (Folder 41)
  - Eckstein, A. M., 1988-1989 (Folder 42)
  - Eddy, Sherwood, 1937 (Folder 43)
  - Edman, Irwin, 1925-1949 (Folder 44)
  - Educational Records Bureau, 1953-1957 (Folder 45)
  - Edwards, Paul, 1947-1969 (Folder 46)
  - Efron, Edith, 1985 (Folder 47)
  - Ehrenreich, Isaac, 1949-1971 (Folder 48)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1935-1952 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Eisenbach, Elliot, 1989 (Folder 2)
  - Eisenstadt, S. N., 1987 (Folder 3)
  - Ellis Island College Committee, 1960 (Folder 4)